A Finding Aid to the Henri Gallery Records, circa early 1900s, 1940-1996, bulk 1957-1995, in the Archives of American Art AAA.henrgall
Archives of American Art
Henri Gallery records
circa early 1900s
bulk 1957-1995
1940-1996
AAA.henrgall
Archives of American Art
54.6 Linear feet
The records of Henri Gallery, a Washington, D.C. gallery that showed painters from the Washington Color School and emerging artists, measure 54.6 linear feet and date from circa early 1900s, 1940 to 1996, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1957 to 1995. The gallery's relationship with artists and clients, exhibitions, sales, and other business is documented in alphabetical files containing a wide variety of materials, including correspondence, sales records, printed materials, photographs and slides. Additional correspondence, newspaper clippings, 114 exhibition posters, scattered drawings, illustrated cards, and photographic materials are also found in the collection.
Henri Gallery (Washington, D.C.).
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 5 series.
Series 1: General Correspondence, 1949-1996 (2.5 linear feet; Boxes 1-3, 55-56)
Series 2: Alphabetical Files, 1947-1996 (50.1 linear feet; Boxes 3-52, 55-57, OV58)
Series 3: Printed Materials, circa early 1900s, 1940-1995 (1.2 linear feet; Boxes 52-53, 57, OVs 59-61)
Series 4: Artwork, 1952-circa 1996 (5 folders; Boxes 53, 57)
Series 5: Photographic Materials, 1940s-1981 (0.8 linear feet; Boxes 53-54, 57)
Biographical/Historical note
In 1957, Henrietta Ehrsam, known as "Henri," opened her eponymous gallery on South Royal Street in Alexandria, Virginia. Earlier, Henri and her partner Florie King had sold clothing, antiques, accessories and decorative arts alongside works of art at their consignment shop "Not New" in the same location.
In the 1960s, Henri showed painters Gene Davis, Thomas Downing, and Howard Mehring of the Washington Color School. In the summer of 1967, Henri Gallery moved to 1500 21st Street NW, closer to the Dupont Circle art galleries in Washington, D.C. Henri showed many young and emerging artists, including Cynthia Bickley-Green, William Christenberry, Mary Beth Edelson, Ed McGowin, and Robert Stackhouse. In 1970, Henri opened a second location, Henri 2, at 1875 Connecticut Ave. NW to exhibit large scale works. In 1972, Henri 2 held Martin Puryear's first solo exhibition in the United States. Henri passed away in 1996 and both gallery locations closed shortly thereafter.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Henri donated the Henri Gallery records in three accessions between 1980 - 1981. Henri's daughter, Helen Schnoebelen donated additional records in 1996.
Scope and Contents note
The records of Henri Gallery, a Washington, D.C. gallery which showed painters from the Washington Color School and emerging artists, measure 54.6 linear feet and date from circa early 1900s, 1940 to 1996, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1957 to 1995. The gallery's relationship with artists and clients, exhibitions, sales, and other business is documented in alphabetical files containing a wide variety of materials, including correspondence, sales records, printed materials, photographs and slides. Additional correspondence, newspaper clippings, 114 exhibition posters, scattered drawings, illustrated cards, and photographic materials are also found in the collection.
General Correspondence includes incoming business correspondence with artists, clients, galleries, and museums, regarding artwork, exhibitions, and other business issues. Also found here are holiday cards, handmade cards, and illustrated correspondence.
The bulk of the records consist of Alphabetical Files contains materials regarding artists, clients, exhibitions, galleries, museums, and various subjects of interest, originally arranged alphabetically by folder title. Folders range in quantity and variety of materials, including correspondence, printed materials, photographs, sales and consignment records, resumes, price lists, and exhibition records. There are especially rich or extensive files for Darryl Abraham, Harry Anderson, Cynthia Bickley-Green, Robert Clements, Mary Beth Edelson, Leslie Exton, Colin Greenly, Mimi Herbert, Traute Ishida, Kiki Kogelnik, Ida Kohlmeyer, Ed McGowin, Tom Nakashima, Graeme Outerbridge, Martin Puryear, Italo Scanga, Robert Stackhouse, Philip Van Brunt, and May Wilson. Of interest is the complete series of Eleanor Antin's 100 Boots postcards.
The bulk of Printed Materials are newspaper clippings regarding artists, exhibitions, and Henri Gallery. There are also 114 posters dating from 1959-1979 from Henri Gallery exhibitions and other galleries' exhibitions of artists in which the Henri Gallery represented.
Artwork is comprised of loose drawings and sketches, many of Henri. Photographic Materials contains black and white photographs, scattered color photographs, snapshots, and slides of artwork, exhibitions, Henri, the galleries spaces, and the Not New shop. Most photographs are undated.
Abraham, Darryl; Anderson, Harry; Antin, Eleanor; Bickley-Green, Cynthia; Clements, Robert; Edelson, Mary Beth; Exton, Leslie; Greenly, Colin, 1928-; Herbert, Mimi; Ishida, Traute; Kogelnik, Kiki; Kohlmeyer, Ida, 1912-1997; McGowin, Ed, 1938-; Nakashima, Tom, 1941-; Outerbridge, Graeme, 1950-; Puryear, Martin, 1941-; Scanga, Italo, 1932-; Stackhouse, Robert; Van Brunt, Philip; Wilson, May, 1905-1986; Art galleries, Commercial--Washington (D.C.); Color-field painting; Drawings; Greeting cards; Illustrated letters; Photographs; Sketches
- General Correspondence, 1949-1996; Series 1; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-3, 55-56
  Scope and Contents note
  General Correspondence includes incoming business and personal correspondence with artists, clients, galleries, and museums, regarding artwork, exhibitions, and other business issues. Also found here are holiday cards, handmade cards, illustrated correspondence, miscellaneous financial correspondence and sales records, scattered photographic materials, and various interfiled exhibition printed materials.
  The folders are arranged chronologically by year; correspondence prior to 1981 is also arranged chronologically by month and day. Unsorted and undated materials, handmade and illustrated correspondence, and other miscellaneous materials are filed at the end of the series.
  - Correspondence, 1956-1985; 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1-19)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1993; 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence, Undated, circa 1949-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
  - Correspondence, Unsorted, 1963-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
  - Correspondence, Unsorted, 1964-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Financial Correspondence [Sales Receipts, Price Lists, Etc.], circa 1958-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Handmade and Illustrated Cards, 1960s-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    Oversized material housed in Box 56, Folder 1
  - Handmade and Illustrated Christmas Cards, 1960s-1981 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Henri Gallery Stationary and Christmas Cards, circa 1957-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Postcards and Greeting Cards, circa 1986-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Restricted Folders, circa 1979 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Handmade and Illustrated Cards, circa 1966 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 3, Folder 5
- Alphabetical Files, 1947-1996; Series 2; 50.1 Linear feet Boxes 3-52, 55-57, OV 58
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  2.1: Name Files, 1947-1996
  2.2: Subject Files, circa 1948-1996
  Alphabetical Files contains materials regarding artists, clients, exhibitions, galleries, museums, and various subjects of interest, originally arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Name Files, 1947-1996; 2.1
    Name Files contains correspondence with artists, clients, galleries, and museums; business and financial records; exhibition printed materials; newspaper clippings; photographic materials; price lists; research files for artists; resumes; sales and consignments receipts; and scattered artwork.
    The quantity and variety of the materials in each folder varies widely. There are especially rich or extensive files for Darryl Abraham, Harry Anderson, Cynthia Bickley-Green, Robert Clements, Mary Beth Edelson, Leslie Exton, Colin Greenly, Mimi Herbert, Traute Ishida, Kiki Kogelnik, Ida Kohlmeyer, Ed McGowin, Tom Nakashima, Graeme Outerbridge, Martin Puryear, Italo Scanga, Robert Stackhouse, Philip Van Brunt, and May Wilson. Of interest is the complete series of Eleanor Antin's 100 Boots postcards.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by name. Unsorted materials are filed at the end of the subseries.
    - A Clean Well Lighted Place, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Abe, N., circa 1957-1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Abraham, Darryl, 1970-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14-19)
    - Abraham, Darryl, 1993 Exhibition (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Abraham, Darryl, Drawings, circa 1970-1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Abraham, Darryl, Illustrated Envelopes, 1971-1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Abraham, Darryl, Statements, 1987-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Ken, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Oversized material housed in Box 56, Folder 2
    - Adams, Mac, 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Adelman, Alice, circa 1975; 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Agard, James, circa 1990s; 1969-1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Albee, Edward, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Aleo, Nancy, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Alexander, Peter, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Alfonso, Ena, circa 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Allen, Ray, circa 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Altman, Edith, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Altman, Edith, [Disassembled Binder], circa 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
    - Amann, Helmut, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Ambo, Kenji, circa 1957-1964 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - The American Institute of Architects (A.I.A.), 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Amundarain, Susana (Venezuela), 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Anderson, Harry, 1970-1995 (Box 4, Folder 19-25)
    - Anderson, Harry, circa 1970-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Anderson, Harry, (Collector), 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Anderson, Harry, Lamp Drawings, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Anderson, Harry, Lamps, circa 1980-1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Anderson, Harry, Receipts, 1975-1993 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Anderson, Harry, Resume, circa 1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Andrews, Benny, 1963-1988 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - Andrews, Kasse, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Andrikopoulos, John, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Antin, Eleanor, 1971-1973; 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
    - Anton, Peter, 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
    - Anton, Peter, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Anton, Peter, Material Returned from Post, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Aoki Gallery [Takenori Hara Sculpture], 1988; 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Appel, Robert, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Archives of American Art, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Arnold, Greta, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Aronson, Jan K., circa 1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Art in Embassies Program, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Artransport, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Arts & Antiques, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Asay, Roger, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ashburgh, Dennis, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Asher, Elise, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Ashley, George, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Astman, Barbara, 1975-1986 (Box 6, Folder 16-19)
    - Attaway, Wayne, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
    - Avedisian, Edward, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Aylon, Helene, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Ayoroa, Rudy, circa 1957-1967 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Baber, Alice, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
    - Baber, Alice and Jane Beach Ekblaw, 1969-1980 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Bach, Kim, circa 1988-1996 (Box 6, Folder 29-31)
    - Bachner, John, Mr. and Mrs., 1972-1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bacon, Francis, 1989; 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Bailey, Roy, circa 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Bailey, Stephany, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Bakaty, Mike, circa 1971-1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Balassanian, Sonia, circa 1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Baldassano, Vincent, 1970-1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Baldessari, Antonio, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Ballard, Robert, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Balsley, John Gerald, 1968-1980 (Box 7, Folder 10-13)
      Oversized material housed in Box 56, Folder 3
    - Balthus, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Bannard, Walter Darby, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Barnes, Curt, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Baronio, Richard, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Barr, Paula, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Barrett, Bill, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Bartolomucci, Giovanni, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Bash, Mary, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Bates, Leo, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Bauer, Eric, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Baynard, Ed, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Bean, Bennett, circa 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Beckman, N.D., circa 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Beer, Kenneth, circa 1961-1963 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Belair-Rigdon, Felicia, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Ben Trè, Howard, 1990-1991; 1980 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Benglis, Lynda, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Benjamin, Karl, 1954-1974 (Box 7, Folder 31-32)
    - Benning, James, 1981; 1974 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Berkowitz, Leon, 1968-1983 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Berlin, Alejandro, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Berman, Eugene, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Bermudez, Jose, 1962-1974 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Bernardin, Maren, circa 1973-1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Berni, Antonio, 1962-1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Berns, Ben, 1966-1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bertoldi, Allen, circa 1969-1975; Includes 1 film reel: Super 8mm (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
      Film titled "Slow Motion"
    - Besossa, Tomas, circa 1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Beuys, Joseph, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Beyer, Steven, circa 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Bickley-Green, Cynthia, 1970-1995 (Box 8, Folder 9-16)
    - Bigger, Michael, 1976-1990 (Box 8, Folder 17-24)
    - Binion, McArthur, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Bisbing, Roger, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Bishop, Nancy, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Blaine, Michael, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Bogdanovitch, Boris, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bohnen, Blythe, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bohrod, Aaron, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bolich, Ferrell, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bonevardi, Marcelo, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bonham, Don, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Booth, Glen, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Booth, Robert, 1979-1996 (Box 9, Folder 10-16)
    - Bourdon, David (critic), 1972-1978 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Bourdon, Robert, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
    - Bourgeois, Louise, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Bowen, Gary, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Bowles, Marianne, 1968-1981 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Bradford, James A., circa 1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Bradley, James, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Bram, Elizabeth, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Branch, Debby, circa 1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Breidel, Joe, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Breimon, Roy C., circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Brennan, Nizette, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Bright, Harold, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Britz, Chris, 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Broches, Alexandra, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Brody, Myron Roy, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Bronner, Wilhelm, 1981-1992 (Box 9, Folder 35-36)
    - Bronner, Wilhelm, Latest, 1983-1992 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Brown, Brenda, 1984-1990 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Brown, Hilton, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Brown, J. Carter, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Brown, Jim, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Brown, Philip, 1972-1977 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Brown, R.G., III, 1989-1995 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Brown, Ronald, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Brown, Valerie, 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Bryant, Laura (fabric), circa 1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Bucher, George A., 1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Buckwalter, Susan, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Budd, Robert, circa 1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Bunch, Clarence, circa 1972, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Bunyon, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Burden, Chris, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Busch, Ralph, 1970-1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Butterfield, Deborah, circa 1985 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Byrd, Elizabeth, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Byrne, J., undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Caballero, José, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Cafritz, Anthony, 1990-1995 (Box 10, Folder 16-19)
    - Cage, John, Obituary, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Cain, J. Frederick, 1975-1994 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Cain, J. Frederick and Larry Cain, 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Cain, Lars, 1982-1991 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Calabro, Richard, 1968-1978 (Box 10, Folder 24-26)
    - Calcagno, Lawrence, 1964-1976 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Calder, Alexander, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Camden, Andrew, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Cannady, Jill, circa 1974 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Capasella, Diane, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Capps, Kenneth, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Carlson, Sherwood, after 1967 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Carmienke, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1963-1966 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Caro, Anthony, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Carr, Wendy, 1987-1992 (Box 11, Folder 3-7)
    - Carrow, Dickson, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Carter, Clarence, 1963-1972 (Box 11, Folder 9-11)
    - Carter, Katherine, 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
    - Carthonesen?, George, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Cavat, Irma, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Cawood, Gary, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Chadwick, Douglas, 1976-1990 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Chalif, Ronnie, 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Champeaus, Paul, circa 1964 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Channin, Richard, 1973-1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Charles, Peter, 1975-1990 (Box 11, Folder 21-25)
    - Chicago, Judy, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Childers, Richard, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Chimes, Thomas, 1966-1990 (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
    - Chin, Hsiao, 1965-1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Christenberry, William, 1969-1988 (Box 12, Folder 7-9)
    - Christenberry, William, Sr., 1974-1975, 1987-1991 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
    - Christopherson, Michael, 1972-1979 (Box 12, Folder 12-13)
    - Chu, Ken, 1987-1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Cindric, Mike, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Citron, Minna, after 1964 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Clark, Michael, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Clausen, Theodore, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 18-19)
    - Cleary, John R., 1990-1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Cleary, Manon Catherine, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Cleary, Shirley Jean, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Clements, Roger, circa 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Clements, Roger, 1968-1991 (Box 13, Folder 1-7)
    - Clements, Samuel, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Climenson, William Douglas, circa 1968 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Clover, Jim, 1985-1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Coates, Ross, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Coatsworth, Elizabeth, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Cohen, Barbara, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Colbert, David, 1984-1985; 1993-1995 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Cole, R., 1977 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Cole, Stephanie Kirschen, 1973-1978 (Box 13, Folder 16-18)
    - Collins, Jerome, 1990-1994 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Collins, Lester, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Comtois, Louis, 1971-1990 (Box 13, Folder 21-24)
    - Cooper, Richard, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Cooper, Susan, 1988-1995 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Cooper, Susan, 1988-1994 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
    - Corbett, Edward, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Cornell, Joseph, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Corrigan, Donald, 1968-1972 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Corten Street Sculpture, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Coté, S., 1977 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Cox, Richard, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Coxe, Simeon, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Craft, Douglas, 1966-1969 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Cragg, Tony, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Craig, John Dean, circa 1977 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Creacy, Herbert, 1974-1980 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Creston, William, circa 1965 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Crimmins, Gerald, 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Crispo, Andrew, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Cropsey, Jasper, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Crosby, Valerie, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Crothers, Brent A., 1990-1993 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Crum, David, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Csengeri, George, circa 1969 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Culbertson, Janet, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Cumming, Robert, 1988-1993 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Cummings, David, 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Cuppaidge, Virginia, circa 1973 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Curtis, K., 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Cutler-Shaw, Joyce, 1974-1976; 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 30-32)
    - Cwik, Larry, 1989-1991 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Da Silva, Alfredo, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Da Silva, Viera, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Dablow, Dean, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Dagley, Mark, 1987-1995 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Danzinger, Joan, 1966-1976 (Box 14, Folder 38-39)
    - Davidovich, Jaime, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Davie, Alan, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Davis, Douglas, 1968-1977 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - Davis, Gene, 1962-1978 (Box 15, Folder 4-7)
    - Davis, Jeff, 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Davis, Rebecca, circa 1976 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Davis, Stuart, 1970-1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Davis, Warren, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Daw, Leila, 1978-1984 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - The D.C. Committee to Promote Washington, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - De Blasi, Anthony, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - De Kooning, Willem, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - De Long, Paul, 1986-1990 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - De Smidt, Thomas, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - De Soto, Hugo, 1964-1971 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - De Witt, Rita, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - De Woody, James, 1983-1989 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Deem, George, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Deffebach, Tex, 1984-1995; 1974 (Box 15, Folder 22-23)
    - Dehn, Adolf, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Dennard, Eric, 1987-1994; 1974 (Box 15, Folder 25-26)
    - Denney, Alice, 1976-1994 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Department of State, 1983-1992 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Dessner, Murray, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Di Domenico, Rebecca, 1983-1989 (Box 15, Folder 30-31)
    - Di Domenico, Rebecca, 1984-1990 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Di Paulo, Giovanni, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Diao, David, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Dickinson, Eleanor, 1975-1979 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Dignac, Geny, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Dionisi, Augusto, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Dix, Otto, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Djordjevic, Predrag (Yugo), 1986-1988 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
      Oversized material housed in Box 56, Folder 4
    - Dobrick Gallery, 1978-1980 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Donhauser, Paul, circa 1977-1980 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Donovan, William, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Dorsey, Deborah, 1989-1995 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Dougherty, Frazer, 1967-circa 1969 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Dower, Natalie, circa 1986-1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Downing, Casey, Jr., 1985-1995 (Box 16, Folder 16-18)
    - Downing, Polly, 1968-1979 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Downing, Thomas, 1987; 1965-1980 (Box 16, Folder 20-22)
    - Doyle, Joe, 1983-1987 (Box 16, Folder 23)